冷锅装满陈年油脂
Cold fryer full of old grease
不劳者不得食
You don't work, you don't eat
风吹不会超过一周
The wind didn't blow for a week
鸟向东飞去寻找绿色
Birds fly east searchin'for green
巢中鸟喙饥渴，金钱推动运作
Open beaks in the nest, money machines
像旗子空中飘动，像是贪婪的巫婆
Flutterin', flags, covetous hags
动作不快就赶不上生活
It's not really movin'if it's not movin'fast
嘴里塞满玻璃
Mouth full of glass
水如镜面，精密剪刀割断毒气
Water like a mirror, cut the gas with precision scissors
如掘墓人埋头将任务做完
Bent to the task as if gravedigger
当它慢下来，彼此将头发剪断
When it was slow cut each other's hair with clippers
子弹穿过死寂空气寻找受害者
Bullets cuttin' through dead air lookin'for victims
VSM标志贴在弹药上
Vickers, VSM stamped on the ammunition
这并不寻常
That's unusual though
通常你坐在这，日以继夜
Usually you sit there, the sun come and go
月亮浮起，马匹被扔下甲板，挣扎后死去
The moon float, horses thrown overboard kick fast, then slow
这真的不重要
It don't really matter which
浓雾渐起，叶子生烟，紧握拳头
Thick mist, piff smoke, draw straws from clenched fists
沉下的船，人类灵魂于船身中
Sinkin' ship, human souls in the hull
他已将全世界握在手中，冰冷无比
He got the whole world in his hands, ice cold
打开他们的手掌，释放黑色的幽灵
Open them palms up, turned black as a ghost
事情发生前，无事发生
Nothin' ever happens "tilitdo
防水的靴子，几乎全新
Waterproof boots, almost new
妈妈摇晃她的脑袋： “你不该穿死人的鞋子
Moms shook her head,"you shouldn't wear a dead man's shoe'
事情被做之前，无事发生
Nothin' ever happens 'til it does
不通过接头人做事全都是麻烦
Muchos problemas if you don't have it for the plug (trust me)
时间到了
Time's up
没有人真正为了爱做这件事
Nobody ever really did it for the love
我们用时间换取药物
We exchange time for drugs
时间堆积，却永远不够
Time piled up. but it was never enough
时间飞逝，当你听别人胡说八道
Time flies when you call a nigga bluff
时间流逝地像月初第一天一样快
Time ran down on us like the first of the month, and dumped
发现他没钱（没枪），便会像乞丐流落街头
Caught him lackin', wakin' up on a park bench a bum
事情发生前，无事发生
Nothin'ever happens 'til itdo
防水的靴子，几乎全新
Waterproof boots, like new
妈妈摇晃她的脑袋： “你不该穿死人的鞋子
Moms shook her head,"shouldn't wear a dead man's shoes"
事情被做之前，无事发生
Nothin'ever happens'til it does
不通过接头人做事全都是麻烦
Muchos problemas if you don't have it for the plug
在这立锥之地，我学会了闭嘴
In tight spaces I learned not to speak
潜艇环绕在山峰周围
Submarine skirtin mountain peaks
如费尔南多波的黑纱监狱
Fernando Po's Black Beach
莫桑比克海岸外的也门商人
Yemeni traders off the coast of Mozambique
拥挤的酒馆里，兄弟们在飞
Packed bodegas, akh in the weeds
金子在暗礁里闪烁
Gold shimmerin' in the reef
非洲的水流淌
African water in the lengths of the piece
黑人先生押进双开门吉普车，倾尽财力
Tha Carter Il pour out a double parked Jeep
雨即刻开始下，我便离开
The rain starts the minute I leave
到了转角水已深至腰部
At the corner the water waist deep
事情发生前，无事发生
Nothin' ever happens 'til it do
防水靴子，防水鞋
Waterproof boots, waterproof boots
事情被做之前，无事发生
Nothin'ever happens'til it does
不通过接头人做事全都是麻烦
Muchas problemas if you don't have it for the plug
翻译及注释@羊与Savior